## Idorenyin Ankoh.

## **Software Quality Assurance Analyst**

Lagos, Nigeria

## **Professional Summary**

An Analytical and detail-oriented individual, able to identify and implement process improvements that increase accuracy, consistency and efficiency. Experienced in Manual & Automated Testing for Software Quality Assurance (SQA), Knowledgeable in Open-Source Automation Tools (Selenium, Jmeter, RestAssured, Postman) and familiar with Programming in Java and JavaScript

## **Experience**

### **TheMullingsGroup**

Florida, USA April 2022 - Current

## **Assurdly Ltd**

Lagos, Nigeria May 2022 - April 2023

## Senior Software QA Analyst

- · Working closely with other team leads to identify and implement process improvements not just for the QA team but company-wide
- Contributed to analyzing the business requirements documents and functional design documents.
- . Tests software to detect bugs and errors. Check whether a product complies with the requirements.
- · Developed and maintained API automation suites using Postman.
- · Assessed functionality, performance, reliability, stability, and compatibility of systems
- · Perform vulnerability scans and advise and report results to the development and DevOps team.
- · Write Web test automation scripts and maintain automation packs

## Senior Software QA Analyst

#### **Team Lead**

- · Conducting training sessions with employees to ensure that they efficiently and effectively execute tasks.
- · Working closely with other team leads to identify and implement process improvements not just for the QA team but company-wide
- · Contributed to analyzing the business requirements documents and functional design documents.
- · Tests software to detect bugs and errors.
- · Developed and maintained API test automation suite.
- Prepared user stories for client solutions and identified quality assurance process bottlenecks and suggested actions for improvement
- · Assessed functionality, performance, reliability, stability, and compatibility of systems
- Investigate product quality to make improvements to achieve better customer satisfaction

#### SoftAlliance and Resources Ltd

Lagos, Nigeria March 2019 - April 2022

### **Software Test Engineer**

- Built and executed Web and mobile automation test frameworks
- Documented user cases and test scripts for APIs to create traceability between both using test rail, Taskhub, and spreadsheet
- · Supervised the activities of other testers to ensure quality
- Executed API test and created automation suite for same using Postman and Restassured.
- Carried out API tests using Restassured, Postman, and SoapUI.
- Implemented and maintained a Continuous testing pipeline using Jenkins and Gitlab.
- Performed monthly performance tests on solutions using Jmeter
- Executed security scans using OWASP ZAP and Burp Suite.

#### Achievements/Awards:

- Busy Bee (Employee who worked really hard all the time)
- · Contagious laughter (Employee who make sure jokes abounds)

## **Some Technical Projects**

#### NIBSS Service-In-A-Box

**Nigeria Inter-Bank Settlement System Plc (NIBSS)** is the largest inter-bank transfer services provider in Nigeria, connecting all the banks and moving over 350m transactions worth N25 trillion a month

NIBSS Service-In-A-Box is a refined single-box solution to achieve NIBSS integration with speed, quality, and efficiency by addressing known issues peculiar to this integration.

JENKINS POSTMAN SOAPUL GITHUB

### CoronationFD

Coronation GPS Limited - is a leader in the financial services industry, with a clear focus on Corporate and Investment Banking, Business Banking, Wealth Management, and Insurance. They are building a digital marketplace for insurance products.

KATALON MANUAL TESTING

#### **Soft Suite**

SoftSuiteHR is designed to address human capital management processes in any organization. Think about everything a human resources (HR) department needs to achieve: workforce planning, recruitment, appraisals, promotions, payroll, payment, keeping track of leave entitlement, getting visibility over project-specific costs, workforce performance, succession planning, regulatory compliance, and providing analysis.

JMETER MANUAL TESTING GITLAB SCANDIUM JIRA

### **Reyts**

**Reyts** makes it easy to swap the currencies you have for the currencies you need seamlessly and securely.

POSTMAN MANUAL TESTING PLAYWRIGHT

## **Skills**

## **Soft Skills**

Communication	Reporting Skills	Team work	Problem-Solving	Leadership

### **Technical Skills**

These skills cover languages, frameworks, libraries, and technical stacks.

API Testing	Web app Testing	Performance Testing	Mobile app Testing
Manual and Automated	Manual and Automated		Mobile and Automation

## Tools, Utilities, and Services

Tools are third-party websites, SAAS products, and support services used during software development

JIRA/Click up/Trello	Jenkins/ Gitlab/ Github/ Azure	Sellenium Webdriver (Java/python/c#)/
(Project Management)	(Devops and CI/CD)	Playwright/ Cypress/ Katalon/ Appium
		(Web and Mobile Automation)

Jmeter/ K6	OWASP ZAP/ BurpSuite	TestRails/Spreadsheet	Restassured/ Postman
(Performance Testing)	(Security Testing)	(Test documentation)	(API Testing)

# **Education and Certifications**

Certifications ISTQB-CTFL -

**Certified Tester Foundation Level** 

ISO 27001

Lead Implementer

## **Education**

University of Uyo, Nigeria Sept. 2012 - July 2017

## **BSc in Economics**

Micro Economics, Macro Economics, Monetary Policy, Operations Research.

- Was the director of Socials of the Social sciences' faculty.
- Was secretary of the house of social of the Student Union Government